illinoisproperty.com 2014-11-30

# Privacy Policy

                                            Privacy Policy
Thank you for visiting illinoisproperty.com or utilizing the our mobile application found at mobile
app stores such as the Apple® App store and Google® Play (the "Web-System"). This privacy
policy only applies to the Web-System. RE/MAX Northern Illinois has established a network of
independently owned and operated offices and their Broker Associates providing real estate
services in the northern Illinois region (the "Network"). The Web-System also hosts websites for
members of the Network ("Network Members"). This Privacy Policy is specific to RE/MAX
Northern Illinois handling of your personal information and does not apply to the privacy
practices of Network Members or 3rd parties. As discussed below, we do provide your
information to Network Members who may, in their sole discretion, transfer your information
to third parties. We do not control the actions of Network Members. By using the Web-
System, you agree that RE/MAX Northern Illinois is not liable for the actions of any Network
Members, including their transfer of your information to third parties. . If you have any
concerns about the privacy practices of Network Members, please contact the Network Member
directly. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy and associated Terms of Use then do not
use the Web-System.
RE/MAX Northern Illinois is committed to safeguarding your privacy on our Web-System. We use
this privacy policy to clearly disclose to you our privacy practices in a manner that is easy to
understand. If there is something you do not understand about our privacy practices, please feel
free to contact Compliance Office at compliance@rfcpinc.com.
This privacy policy does not apply to products or services provided, or information obtained,
other than through the Web-System. We may change this policy from time to time so please
check back often. If we significantly change our collection, use, or disclosure practices, we will
try to send you a notice via email if you have provided us with an email address. Please keep in
mind that some of the services mentioned specifically in this policy may not be available on the
site at this time. This Privacy Policy is effective as of March 1, 2014.
What information does RE/MAX Northern Illinois collect from you?
We collect information in several ways. Some of the information we collect is personal to you.
Other information is anonymous. We collect the following categories of information:
        During registration, we ask for your name, email address, and phone number and other
         profile information about your home buying needs.
        When you report a problem with our site or services we will collect contact information
         along with a description of your problem
        When you contact us via the company email address, we will collect your contact
         information and any information you include in your email
        To customize our service for you, we and our partners may collect precise location data,
         including the real-time geographic location of your computer or device. This location data
         is collected anonymously in a form that does not personally identify you.
DB04/1001225.0002/10710912.1 DOC

        When you visit and navigate our site, use our applications or third party sites, or open our
         emails, we may collect technical information about your use of our site including IP
         address, device identifier, and viewing information.
        We may collect information to populate real estate forms to help you enter into real
         estate transactions with your real estate broker and your 3rd party service provider for
         mortgage, title, home warranty etc.
How do we collect information from you?
Direct Collection
We collect much of the information listed above directly from you when you submit it on our
Web-System. This includes information such as registration information, contact information,
user submissions, real estate form information, and public postings. If you do not want to share
your information, you can choose not to participate in a particular service or activity.
Indirect Collection – Cookies and Other Technology
As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, many websites use
cookies and other online tracking technologies to store and sometimes track information about
you. We may use these technologies to:
        Provide you with personalized content based on your use of our site
        Enable you to more easily use our site by remembering and using contact information,
         purchasing information, and registration information
        Evaluate, monitor and analyze the use of our site and its traffic patterns to help improve
         our site and services
        Assist us with ad reporting functions such as to learn which ads are bringing users to our
         website
The types of technologies we use include:
        Cookies. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web
         server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies enable us to identify your
         browser as a unique user. Cookies may involve the transmission of information from us
         to you and from you to us. Cookies may also be used by another party on our behalf to
         transfer information to us in accordance with their privacy policy. Some cookies are
         "persistent cookies." They are used by us each time you access our Web-System. Other
         cookies are called "session cookies." Session cookies are used only during a specific
         browsing session. We may use a session cookie, for example, to remember that you have
         already navigated through a particular menu, or that you have entered in age information
         for a portion of a site that is restricted by age. We may also use "analytics cookies" that
         allow web analytics services to recognize your browser or device and, for example,
         identify whether you have visited our Web-System before, what you have previously
                                                     2
DB04/1001225.0002/10710912.1 DOC

         viewed or clicked on, and how you found us. This information is provided anonymously
         for statistical analysis only. Analytics cookies are usually persistent cookies.
You may disable browser cookies in your browser or set your browser to warn you when a cookie
is being sent. You may lose some features or functionality when you disable cookies. Remember,
also, that disabling cookies is browser specific. If you log on using Internet Explorer, you must
also disable cookies in Safari if you use that browser at a different time.
     Web Beacons. We also employ a software technology called a clear GIF (Graphics
         Interchange Format), also known as a pixel tag or Web beacon. A clear GIF is a line of
         code that we place on our websites or in emails which allows us to analyze our advertising
         and the general usage patterns of visitors to our websites. These help us better manage
         content on our site by informing us what content or promotions are effective. Unless you
         consent, we do not collect personally identifiable information from you through the use
         of web beacons. You may not disable Web beacons.
     Log Files. Like most standard website servers, we use log files. Log files track Internet
         protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages,
         platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We utilize this information to
         analyze trends, administer the site, prevent fraud, track website navigation in the
         aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.
     Flash Cookies. Flash cookies, also known as local shared objects, are used to store
         preferences such as video volume, or display content based on what you view on our site
         using the Adobe Flash Player. Flash cookies are not stored through the browser.
         Advertisers and third party service providers may use Flash cookies to collect and store
         information.         Information about disabling Flash cookies may be found at
         www.adobe.com. If you disable Flash cookies, you may lose some features or
         functionality on our site.
Indirect Collection – Social Networking
The website permits you to use a third party social networking platform such as Facebook,
Linked-In, Twitter, and Google+. This includes use of social media plugins such as Facebook
"Like," Tweet, Google "+1" buttons, etc. When you use these social networking platforms and
plugins, your username and password for the available about you or collected from you on these
services may be shared with us. When you use social networking platforms and plugins, you
share your information with them and their privacy policy applies disclosure of such information.
In addition, they may be able to collect information about you, including your activity or may
notify your connections on the social networking platform about your use of the Company's
websites. Such services may allow your activity to be monitored across multiple websites for
purposes of delivering more targeted advertising. Please note that their own privacy polices
apply and we encourage you to read them. We may add new social networking plugins and
buttons to our websites from time to time.
                                                    3
DB04/1001225.0002/10710912.1 DOC

Indirect Collection – Third Party Advertising Services
We may employ over time various different advertising or remarketing services that serve you
targeted advertisements to make your online experience more focused to your interests. These
services may place a remarketing pixel and/or on the website in order to recognize your browser
and serve advertisements that relate to prior searches and activities you participate in on the
Web-System. We will not run interest-based advertising campaigns that collect personally
identifiable information (PII) including, but not limited to, email addresses, telephone numbers
and credit card numbers. We will not use or associate personally identifiable information with
remarketing lists, cookies, data feeds or other anonymous identifiers. We will not use or
associate targeting information, such as demographics or location, with any personally
identifiable information collected from the ad or its landing page(s).
We will not share any personally identifiable information with Google through our remarketing
tag or any product data feeds which might be associated with our ads.
We may use third party services we to manage these technologies and to serve advertisements
on our Web-System example, we may employ technology that pairs specific advertisements our
site and others with searches that you run on our website. In order to provide this type of
targeted advertising. We will not run interest-based advertising campaigns that collect personally
identifiable information (PII) other than anonymous persistent identifiers. We will not track your
ad preferences by email addresses, telephone numbers or credit card numbers. We will not use
or associate personally identifiable information with remarketing lists, cookies, data feeds or
other anonymous identifiers. We also use Google Analytics and Site Master to analyze your use
of our Web-System and the use of others. Analytical data is kept anonymous.
How do we use your information?
Our main goal in collecting information is to improve the site and provide you with the best
possible experience on the site. For example, by using the information we collect, we can provide
you with an easy to use and readily available forum to learn about our services and receive MLS
information. We also share information with Network Members to enable you to find agents and
properties in your area. If a Network Member further shares you information outside of the
Web-System, that information is governed by the privacy practices of that Network Member. We
may use information you submit in real estate forms to help you enter into real estate
transactions with your real estate broker, mortgage lender and title company, and other services.
We will also use your personal information to:
        Establish a non-exclusive Consumer-real estate broker relationship in order to enable you
         to receive certain non-public MLS data (see our Terms of Use under Consumer-real estate
         broker Relationship)
        Notify you of services available from our network of real estate brokers
        Enable you to search for real estate brokers and properties
                                                  4
DB04/1001225.0002/10710912.1 DOC

        Personalize online content so that is applies to you and your interests
        Make our services and Web-System better
        To notify you of enhancements or changes to the Web-System
        Compile, analyze, and do research on our users demographics and behavior
        Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal
We use and share location data only to provide and improve our service.
Who is collecting information?
Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, only RE/MAX Northern Illinois and our service providers,
and our network of real estate brokers will have access to your personal account information.
When you are on our site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that
information with RE/MAX Northern Illinois, our service provider, and our network independently
owned offices and their sales associates. If personal data is to be collected and/or maintained
by any company other than RE/MAX Northern Illinois or its service providers or network
independently owned offices and their sales associates, we will try to notify you on the website
or in an updated version of this Privacy Policy. If you do not want your data to be shared, you
can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service.
Other websites to which we link may collect personally identifiable information about you when
you visit those sites. The information practices of other websites linked to our websites are not
covered by this Privacy Policy.
With whom does RE/MAX Northern Illinois share my information?
We will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your
permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law
requires it or under the circumstances described below. These are some of the ways that your
information may be disclosed.
Real Estate Transactions
We may share your information with Network Members in order to put you in contact with the
right office and real estate broker and for the promotional purposes of the Network Members.
We may share information from forms with 3rd parties who have sponsored the forms or parties
related to the transaction who are working with you or your real estate broker.
Service Providers
We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including
packaging, delivering, or mailing, website development and operation, answering customer
questions about products or services, sending postal mail or email, analyzing website use,
processing payments, providing investor information and processing data. We will only provide
                                                   5
DB04/1001225.0002/10710912.1 DOC

those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are contractually
prohibited from using that information for any other reason.
Data in the Aggregate
We may disclose "blinded" aggregated data and user statistics to prospective partners and other
third parties. Blinded data is data that does not identify an individual person.
Other
We also may disclose your information in special cases. For example, when we believe that we
must disclose information to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be
violating our Terms and Conditions of Use, or may be causing injury to or interference with our
rights or property, other website users or customers, or anyone else who may be harmed by such
activities. We may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the
law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain,
service and improve our products and services.
As we continue to develop our business, we may buy or sell businesses or assets. In such
transactions, confidential customer information generally is one of the transferred business
assets. In the event of a transaction involving the sale of some or all of RE/MAX Northern Illinois'
businesses, customer and site visitor information may be one of the transferred assets and may
be disclosed in connection with negotiations relating to a proposed transaction. In such case, the
transferred information may become subject to a different privacy policy.
How can I control my personal information?
If you have a concern about your personal information, please contact us at the email address
provided in this Privacy Policy. We will use good faith efforts to attempt to assist you. .
What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of my
information?
Your Company Account Information and Company Profile is password-protected so you have
access to this personal information. Remember to sign out of your Company account and close
your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot
access your account by using your computer when you are away from it. Because information
sent through the Internet travels from computer to computer throughout the world, when you
give us information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country
where you originally entered the information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the
Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Except as specifically stated, this site does not
use security encryption measures. Information that you disclose by use of this site (as with any
site that is non-secure), by posting a message or using email, potentially could be collected and
used by others. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties or use of such
                                                  6
DB04/1001225.0002/10710912.1 DOC

information by third parties for their own purposes, legal or illegal. As a result, while we strive
to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any
information you transmit to us or from our services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we
receive your transmission, we use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our
systems. The My Property Finder and/or My REMAX sections of the Web-System are not secure.
Files uploaded may be accessed in a general library that is available on the Internet without
password security.
Choice/Opt-out
To ensure that you will not receive recurring marketing or other information from us unless you
choose to, we will provide you with simple instructions on each marketing email from RE/MAX
Northern Illinois for you to let us know that you have chosen to stop receiving such emails from
us.
What else should I know about my privacy?
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose information online, that information
is accessible to other customers and users. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining
the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible
whenever you are online.
When you or we end your customer relationship with us, we will treat the information we have
about you as if you were still our customer.
Who do users contact with questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy?
If you need further assistance, please send an email with your questions or comments to
compliance@rfcpinc.com or write us at:
RE/MAX Northern Illinois
Attention: Compliance Office
2205 Point Blvd Suite 100
Elgin IL, 60123
                                                 7
DB04/1001225.0002/10710912.1 DOC
